

Summary

5 years of experience mainly with backend related technologies.

Also interested in DevOps and data science solutions as well.

Eager to continuously learn while working on challenging projects within a team.

Contact

- Budapest, Hungary
- **2** zoltan.umlauf@gmail.com
- in /in/zoltan-umlauf
- /uzoltan

Languages

English: professional working proficiency

Hungarian: native proficiency

Interests

- Table tennis
- Reading
- Board games
- Hiking
- Logic puzzles
- Software craftsmanship

Zoltán Umlauf

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer

@ Turbine Al

09/2021 - Present

- Designed and developed new features in Turbine's human cell simulation platform, making the jobs of biologists more efficient.
- Constructed machine learning problems to train deep learning models. Evaluated these models on various success criteria.
- · Significantly improved the quality of existing production code.
- Performed a wide range of data engineering tasks.

Python, Pandas, Azure Cloud, AzureML, Databricks, Airflow, GitHub Actions, MongoDB

Senior Software Developer

@ Grape Solutions

03/2019 - 08/2021

- Developed <u>Mobiliti</u>, the largest provider of electric vehicle charging and other e-mobility services in Hungary.
- Discussed software architecture decisions with the team.
- Improved the development workflow, which reduced the complexity of our releases and increased productivity.
- Planned and executed the integration with 4 partners.
- · Learned the basics of DevOps with Docker and Kubernetes.

Java 11, Kotlin, Spring Boot 2, Reactive Streams, Liquibase, JUnit5, Mockito, Gradle, Docker, Google Cloud Platform, MySQL, MongoDB

Software Developer

@ AITIA International

06/2017 - 02/2019

• Participated in a European research and innovation project with 108 partners from over 19 countries. Contributed to the design and development of a framework for the project over the span of 3 years. Familiarized new partners with the framework and reviewed code written by them.

Java 8, JAX-RS, Spring Boot 2, Hibernate, Maven, RabbitMQ, R

Education

MSc in Electrical Engineering

@ Budapest University of Technology and Economics

02/2016 - 01/2018

BSc in Electrical Engineering

@ Budapest University of Technology and Economics

09/2012 - 01/2016

